Good Morning, Church!
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers all over the world, we salute your faith.
Thank You, Lord.
Today we talk about the Word - the Word of God.
As we all know: Faith is of man's heart.
And the Bible says in the Book of Romans:
Anything that does not come from faith is sin.
That is, anything that does not come from the heart.
So that is, man's spirit; it's sin, it's wrong.
Hallelujah!
Take your reading with me to the Book of Isaiah 55 Verse 10.
It will also be a very important passage for you to read.
We read the Book of Hebrews Chapter 4.
And also the Book of Ephesians 3; when you look at verse 17 there, it will also be of help.
John 3 will help us.
Hallelujah!
I can't hear you.
[Amen.]
Also take your reading from the Book of John 15; verse 17 too will be of help in our reading.
So let's take that Book of Hebrews.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"Therefore, since the promise of entering his rest still stands,
let us be careful that none of you be found to have fallen short of it.
For we also have had the good news proclaimed to us, just as they did;
but the message they heard was of no value to them
because they did not share the faith of those who obeyed.
Now we who have believed enter that rest, just as God has said..."
The word rest, rest rest - take note of that rest, rest.
"For anyone who enters God's rest also rests from their works"
That is, also rests from their struggles, tension, pressure. Take note of that.
When you enter God's rest, you also rest from tension, pressure.
"...just as God did from his.
Let us, therefore, make every effort to enter that rest.
so that no one will perish by following their example of disobedience.
For the Word of God is alive and active. Sharper than any double-edged sword..."
Like I have said, on getting home, read the Book of Isaiah 55:10; it will help.
Ephesians 3:17 will help.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
FAITH IS OF MAN'S HEART
But, there is Bible language that God uses to save us,
to create us, to judge us and to rule over us - that is Bible language,
which is language of the heart.
Faith is of man's heart but today's language we use to gossip, give directions, do politics.
You know politics today all over the world.
Today's language is not Bible language
That is why it is difficult for Christians to involve in politics today
because they use today's language to do politics, even to do business,
to sing songs and to talk to our children.
We say, "Get out of this place, stupid!"
We don't mean it but the word of the heart means it.
Tthink of how many times you have booed your children,
"Get out of this place. Please, stupid, idiot."
You don't mean it but your heart means it.
Tell your neighbour.
That is why God's language is 'Word of Heart'; Bible language is 'Word of Heart'.
But you don't mean it.
A lot of business, when you check today you see many people with business cards.
"I am a contractor, I am an architect, I am a lawyer, I am an engineer, I am this" - a lot of business cards.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We use today's language to pray.
You see people today using today's language.
They don't even know the difference between the language of the Bible and today's language.
People use today's language to pray.
That is why whatever they say in their prayer, they don't mean it
and whatever they receive seems not to be permanent because it is mere words.
"Abide in me, come into my life, save my soul, I am a sinner.
Today, Lord Jesus, I will follow You to the end of my life."
But the next day, you will see them somewhere else.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Freedom today, bondage tomorrow because when you are receiving healing, you say,
"Lord, heal me, heal me. I will give my life to you. Heal me."
After your healing - because what you are saying is not from your heart.
So we use today's language to pray, to counsel, to prophesy.
You see some prophecies will say, "Ah, it will rain tomorrow".
But you will find that there is no rain because they don't mean what they are saying.
It is not from their hearts.
FAITH IS OF MAN'S HEART
When the Word is in your heart, it will preserve you from desiring sin.
That is the Word of God.
You need the Word of God in your heart to bring Jesus to the scene.
You cannot say, " In Jesus' name," and expect Jesus,
when what you are saying is not from your heart.
When you don't mean it and you say, "In Jesus' name. Lord Jesus, do this for me, give me this" -
all what you are saying is not from your heart and you are expecting Jesus to come.
The Word in your heart can only bring Jesus to the scene.
The Word of God is the living presence of that divine power
if that Word comes from the heart.
Are you with me?
If that Word comes from the heart;
it is the living presence of that divine power that heals, saves and delivers.
But if the Word is not from the heart, you are just talking to yourself;
you are saying the word of today.
People use the word of today to pray, to counsel, to evangelise, to prophesy.
You say, "Ah, I don't want to smoke it". You come to church, you don't want to smoke.
If this word is not from your heart, it cannot influence your conduct and character.
It is the Word from the heart that can influence your conduct and character.
The Word from the heart takes the place of the unseen Jesus.
Meditation in the Word is a visit with God.
In Jesus' name.
That meditation from the heart - a visit to Jesus.
You become a part of the Word by meditation.
You have to get hold of your heart.
What is going on in your heart?
Locate me in Your mercy, oh Lord.
More of You.
This should continue; your heart should continue saying this while looking at me.
Meditation brings revelation.
By the time you are busy saying this, you will suddenly see who is talking here.
I'm not the one talking, but because you are not in the vision, you are not inspired yet.
You are still seeing a man talking to you. No, I'm not the one talking to you.
You have to know, you have to see who is talking to you now.
By revelation.
Meditation brings revelation.
Continue, turn it over and over again in your heart
Locate me in Your mercy, Lord Jesus.
Take more of me; give me more of You - more of Your faithfulness,
more of Your obedience, more of Your purity, holiness, Lord.
Busy, busy then the revelation comes; you will now see who is talking.
You will see that this is not the man that is talking, "Aha I said it; he is not the one".
Now after the revelation, God will take you back again to your real self.
You will now say, "Oh, I'm back again".
You switch again; this is the life you should live.
Switch on, on.
There are a lot of melodies that should be going on in your heart,
a lot of spiritual songs, hymns.
You have songs; you know a lot of songs you can continue to engage your heart with.
I have seen the downfall of satan
Glory be to God
Glory be to Jesus
That should continue in your heart.
I have seen the downfall of satan
Glory be to God
Amen
Continue in your heart.
Continue this in your heart.
Keep your heart busy while looking at me.
If you cannot see beyond me, it means you are not engaged in God's project.
You must see beyond me to believe.
Tell your neighbour
You must see beyond your pastor to believe.
Just your pastor you used to see.
Every day you go to church, you see your pastor moving.
No. You cannot believe.
You must see beyond your pastor. Beyond him is the Person talking.
Tell your neighbour.
Beyond him - the Person talking .
Beyond him - the Person preaching.
That is all. It is not your pastor.
You keep seeing your pastor every day.
You are not going to church; you are just a religious person.
Religious person - that is all.
You must see beyond. To see beyond is that meditation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What will hinder us?
What is the reason why you cannot do what I am asking you to do now?
Our human nature will.
This has a lot to do with hindering God when there are some mixtures -
part spirit, part flesh in the heart of man, a constant conflict between flesh and spirit.
Some will say, "Don't listen to him. - Listen to him.
Is it possible what he is saying? - It is possible.
Ah, I don't know; what is that? - No, I have tried it before, try it again".
A constant conflict between flesh and spirit.
A struggle between faith and doubt .
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Little time you say, "Take more of me, give me more of You. Locate me in Your mercy.
Ah, what does the time say?"
You have abandoned what you are meditating.
"Take more of me. Give me more of You."
After little time you say, "Can you help me? Just switch that station, the channel to…"
You have forgotten what you are talking.
A struggle between faith and doubt.
A constant conflict between flesh and spirit when there is division in the heart of man.
John 3 says, find out the truth and the truth will set you free.
Wrong, mistake, sin is never covered by our appearance.
You put on tie, collar, big Bible, cross, garment, big cap.
Sin, wrong, mistake is never covered by our appearance, presence, prayer or tears.
Sin is never covered.
Sin can only be removed by repentance.
If our appearance cannot cover our sin, our mistake,
why are we wasting our time over appearance as if it is part of the deal.
How you look cannot cover your sin, your mistake.
Your presence whatever majestic has nothing to do with this.
You must bring your wrong, your mistake, your sin before the Blood of Jesus
before the Spirit prays through you.
Tell your neighbour again.
I must bring my wrong, my mistake, my sin before the Blood of Jesus
before the Spirit prays through me.
We don't know how to pray; the Spirit prays.
We cannot do the work of God; the Spirit of God does.
Think about that.
Majesty
Worship His Majesty
Unto Jesus
Be all glory, honour and praise
Majesty
Kingdom authority
Flows from His throne
Unto His own
His anthem raise
So exalt
Lift up on high
The name of Jesus
Magnify
Come glorify
Christ Jesus the King
Majesty
Worship His Majesty
Jesus who died
Now glorified
King of all kings
Jesus who died
Now glorified
King of all kings
Jesus who died
Now glorified
King of all kings
Majesty
Worship His Majesty
Unto Jesus
Be all glory, honour and praise
Majesty
Kingdom authority
Flows from His throne
Unto His own
His anthem raise
So exalt
Lift up on high
The name of Jesus
Magnify
Come glorify
Christ Jesus the King
Majesty
Worship His Majesty
Jesus who died
Now glorified
King of all kings
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Where shall we start now?
I'm talking about your life.
You cannot continue this way.
You have much, much, much to do.
Don't let your age deceive you.
Don't let your wealth deceive you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is the Spirit of God that can maintain when it comes to maintenance.
You can achieve in whatever way but to maintain, nothing can maintain it except God.
There is no way you can maintain your career.
Look at our leaders, our heroes, the most powerful in the world - you read about them.
Many of them failed to maintain their profile.
That you do not mean what you are saying does not mean you cannot receive healing.
You will receive healing, if you don't mean it. You say, "Ok, let me just come here".
And you don't mean what you are saying but you have problems.
The problem can be solved but to maintain that...
It is better not to receive than to lose.
But the people that say "Congratulations!" will later see you and say, "What is wrong again?"
You start crying, "What is all this?"
This is why I am asking, where shall we start?
Since we know what hinders us is our human nature.
Like I have said:
This has a lot to do with hindering God in your life.
Tell your neighbour.
This has a lot to do with hindering God in our life
when the human will is not wholly surrendered
Your will refuses to surrender.
You want to go there and the will of God says, "No, don't go", and you say, "I will go".
There is a discretion everyone has; you have discretion.
Look at the man at the pool of Bethesda.
Jesus asked him, "What can I do for you?"
He had the power and the grace to carry him.
When you are in trouble, let Him carry you; drop him in this pool.
Instead he said, "Oh, what can I do for you? Do you want me to help you or not?"
And the man said, "Please, help me".
You have discretion; that discretion is a special blessing for you.
You can say, "No, what T.B. Joshua is saying is nonsense.
I can't understand what he is saying".
You have the right.
I surrender
I surrender all
All to Thee
My blessed Saviour
I surrender all
All to Thee
My blessed Saviour
I surrender all
All to Jesus I surrender
All to Him I freely give
I will ever love and trust Him
In His presence daily live
I surrender all
All to Thee
My blessed Saviour
I surrender all
Part spirit, part flesh - a constant conflict between flesh and spirit.
That is the struggle you are going through,
A constant conflict between flesh and spirit.
If God is coming, your heart is the contact point
but in that heart, there is a constant conflict.
There is a battle.
Go - don't go.
Take - don't take.
This is where you are.
When you want to pray, "Lord Jesus, help me to get there",
something will be telling you too, "You will not get there".
This is why I am saying,
don't let your wealth deceive you; you have not got there.
The richest man in your family - you say, "Oh, he has succeeded"; you want to be like him.
How do you know he has succeeded? Because of wealth?
Man's natural gift cannot make one succeed.
Success is all about the spirit, supernatural.
You can suddenly die and leave, and the enemy will start sharing them.
If our leaders know this, superiority complex and all these fights, will cease -
if they know they are not what they think they are.
Vanity upon vanity.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What shall I render
What shall I render to You oh Lord
I will praise You oh Lord
And shout hallelujah
What shall I render to You oh Lord
What shall I render
I will praise You oh Lord
And shout hallelujah
What shall I render to You oh Lord
What your heart is telling you, saying about you, is what you are.
What your heart is telling you now is what you are.
Tell your neighbour.
Tell yourself. Speak to yourself.
What my heart is telling me now is what I am.
Listen to your heart.
When you wake up in the morning and you want to go somewhere, just listen to your heart.
Your heart will say, "Go; don't go".
Heart is about meditation.
You have been living in a thinking processing, not meditation processing.
Tell your neighbour.
There is a difference - meditation is about God; thinking is about our problems.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
People can see you as a poor man but your heart is telling you, "You are great".
Indeed, you are great.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You see a poor man and it is hard to be saying, "Oh, you are great".
Indeed he is great.
But while you rich, your heart will be telling you, "You are the poorest in the world".
Upon the culture, money you are seeing - yet the heart is saying it is poor.
So it means such money will not last.
Whatever you cannot enjoy to the last is not of God.
If what you are cannot be witnessed by generations yet unborn
it means it is not for generations and God is of generations.
God is of generations.
Whatever you are that cannot be witnessed by generations yet unborn,
is not of God because God is of generations.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, please, let's build our life.
Commit your life to God for generations yet unborn to witness and see.
What you are enjoying today, some had paid the supreme price to bring them.
Heart means, 'mean it'.
Tell your neighbour
I can't understand.
Heart means, 'mean it'.
Whatever comes from the heart, we mean it.
This is why each time I'm praying for you, I say, "Mean it, mean it".
It is a place where there is no doubt.
Mean it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Mean it. Mean what you are saying.
In your heart, talk to yourself in hymns, songs and melodies.
We are created to keep our heart busy with the Lord.
Keep your heart praising God; that is what you are created for.
Our heart must be busy praising God.
But your heart has been...
Can you imagine how old you are now?
Your heart has been roaming about.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are created to keep our heart busy for God, praising God.
Busy, busy, busy.
At the beginning, it may look very difficult.
The beginning of everything is always very difficult.
But as time goes on, it will be part of you.
Keep your heart praising God.
I will praise You
I will praise You forever more
For Your goodness
I will praise You
I will praise You forever more
For your kindness
I will praise You
I will praise You forever more
Keep your heart praising God in songs, hymns and melodies.
That is what you were created for, and when you start this, you will come back and give testimony.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, you are supposed to know God's opinion about yourself.
No matter what you are, no matter what you acquire, no matter how great you are,
if you don't know God's opinion about yourself and about others,
whatever you acquire is zero.
The first place we are to prosper is in our spiritual life.
Tell your neighbor
Tell your neighbour.
The first place we are to prosper is in our spiritual life.
I can't hear you.
Again and again.
The first place we are to prosper is in our spiritual life.
Yes. because your spiritual life is the engine that will carry your success.
If you prosper financially and you are just like a little baby in your spiritual life,
that money you have will be spent by the enemy.
You take it to care for sickness, to run from one problem to another,
to run for medical Check-up.
You will realise that the money will be spending you instead of you spending the money.
You know money can be spending one.
You are supposed to spend your money but instead, the money will now be the one to spend you.
You will not be able to eat any food you want to eat.
There will be certain food you should not eat and certain food you should eat.
If you try to eat other food, you will be in trouble.
You have so much medication you have to take in the morning, afternoon, evening.
You start seeing yourself that way.
The first place we are to prosper is in our spiritual life
If you are not prospering in your spiritual life and you are great,
your greatness will be fading away gradually because there is nothing to carry it.
So that is why you have to take your time.
Leave that money, pray.
Find time to pray; don't let money control you.
Let the Giver of that money control you.
But today, what is happening? Where are you living?
Because you have money, where you were living before,
you have to leave the place and live where rich people live.
Money is the one controlling you.
Do you know where you started?
Do you know your beginning? Where are you living now?
You live among the rich because you are a rich man.
That is money control; not the Giver of the money.
The rich are living together and the poor are living together. Who will help the poor?
And you are blessed to bless others.
You are blessed to bless others; you are saved to save others -
that is the purpose of your blessing.
You are blessed to bless others.
This is the cause of the problem now all over the world.
If God gives you breakthrough and you become so rich, and you are now mismanaging, misbehaving.
His peace you cannot run away with.
You can run away with riches, wealth but His peace of heart, you cannot run away with.
So like people sitting down now, they are looking for prayer, they want prayer.
You are here for breakthrough in your business but after the prayer, you have breakthrough,
billions of dollars - you receive it , and then you say, "Ah, I have received it" and you run from God.
But His peace, you cannot go away with it.
You will run away with the money, run away with wealth, run away with the fame, but the peace of God...
God will be looking at you to see the money you have taken, He has given you -
how you spend it will determine the peace of God in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So this is what is happening all over the world today.
This why you see so many rich, wealthy people all over the world without peace.
How do we know that they don't have peace?
The conflict among them will tell you that these people have no peace.
But if you have peace of heart, people are insulting you, beating you, you will be saying, "Take it easy".
Peace does not want conflict. He wants peace.
Peace is always fighting for peace, unity, love.
When He gives you that greatness, He will hold on with this peace to be monitoring you
to see how you go about your greatness.
That will determine how He will release the peace.
So please, the first place we are to prosper is in our spiritual life.
You are to go back to your drawing board.
Tell your neighbour, "Go back".
Go back to the college of God and seek the Spirit of God.
Yes, you are to go back.
If you know you have plenty - money, property - please, go back.
Man live without peace.
Are you one of them?
God bless His Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT Monica Asefa 26/11/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 16/12/2018